# YU CAO

# **Computational Linguist**

 pterosdiacos.github.io

in www.linkedin.com/in/yu-cao-pdiacos

# **EXPERIENCES**

### **Ontology Linguist**

#### Facebook via PRO Unlimited

**10/2019 10/2019** 

Redmond, WA

- Worked at Assistant Cross-Functional Group.
- Prototyped models for cross-domain semantic parsing for question answering, using *PyTorch*.
- Automated inferences and sub-ontology extraction in OWL 2 ontology knowledge graphs, using *Python*.

## **Teaching Assistant**

## **Rutgers University**

**1** 09/2018 - 08/2020

New Brunswick, NJ

• Courses taught: Intro to Linguistic Theory, Invented Languages.

#### Research Assistant

## The Chinese University of Hong Kong

**12/2014 - 07/2015** 

♦ Hong Kong, China

- Worked at Center for Sign Linguistics and Deaf Studies.
- Provided linguistic expertise and assisted in developing a Chinese grammatical knowledge assessment software for deaf/hard of hearing children.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Rutgers University**

#### Ph.D. in Linguistics

## 09/2016 - Present

New Brunswick, NJ

The Chinese University of Hong Kong

M.A. in Chinese Linguistics & Language Acquisition

**1** 09/2013 - 06/2014

♥ Hong Kong, China

Sichuan Normal University

B.A. in Teaching Chinese as a Second Language

**1** 09/2009 - 06/2013

Chengdu, China

# **PUBLICATIONS**

 Automated fact-value distinction in court opinions European Journal of Law and Economics 2020.

▲ Yu Cao, Daniel Chen & Elliot Ash.

Automated classification of fact vs. value statements in written judicial decisions.

Investigating BERT's knowledge of language: Five analysis methods with NPIs

Proceedings of EMNLP 2019.

▲ Alex W., Yu Cao & 14 others (equal contribution). Supervisor: Sam Bowman. Team role: constructed and conducted the main transfer learning experiments.

# **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

**Linguistics** specialized in computational

linguistics, semantics, syntax, discourse analysis. Strong critical-thinking and problem-

solving skills.

Computation 10+ years of experiences in

algorithms and data structure. The First Prize in National Olympiad in Informatics in Provinces 2007, China.

# **PROJECTS**

# Graph representation of meaning

(dissertation research () repo)

- Designed a graph based semantic representation that encodes natural language quantification and plurality.
- Developed a CCG-based semantic parser constructing graphs from texts using *Python*.

# Incremental topological sorting (LingBuzz post)

- Designed algorithms for topological sorting under uncertain conditions.
- Improved on resorting time complexity with dynamic updating strategies.

# **SKILLS**

#### **Technical**

- Machine learning algorithms, NLP/NLU
- Python, C, Scikit-learn, PyTorch, Tensorflow
- Linguistic analysis, symbolic logic, statistics

#### **ML/NLP Coursework**

Natural language processing

**1** 09/2020

Introduction to deep learning

**1** 07/2020

m HSE@Coursera

Machine learning

**∰** 07/2020

<u>m</u> Stanford@Coursera

• Seminar: Linguistic knowledge in reusable sentence encoders

**1** 05/2019

**m** NYU

Graph formalisms for meaning representations
m 07/2018
m NASSLLI@CMU

#### Languages

ENG (fluent) CHN (native) JPN (JLPT N1)